The easiest place to start using window functions is with functions that just count.
أسهل طريقة للبدء في استخدام دوال النافذة هي استخدام الدوال التي تعدّ فحسب.
They don't actually aggregate.
فهي لا تقوم بالتجميع في الواقع.
Row number does just what it sounds like.
تقوم ROW_NUMBER بالضبط بما يوحي به اسمها.
It displays the number of a given rows within the window you define.
فهي تعرض رقم صف محدد ضمن النافذة التي حددتَها.
It starts at one and numbers the rows
تبدأ العد من 1 وترقّم الصفوف
according to the order by part of the window statement.
وفقاً لجزئية ORDER BY في عبارة إنشاء النافذة.
Row number does not require you to specify a variable within the parentheses.
لا تتطلب ROW_NUMBER منك تحديد متغيّر داخل القوسين.
Here, we're ordering by the ID field which increments by 1 every row.
هنا، نحن نرتّب حسب الحقل id الذي يزيد بمقدار 1 في كل صف.
So the ID and row num fields always have the same value.
أي أن الحقلين id و row_num لديهما نفس القيمة دائماً.
But if we order by occurred at,
لكن إذا رتبنا حسب occurred_at،
the rows are ordered differently,
فستترتب الصفوف بشكل مختلف،
and the row num column is therefore assigned differently.
وبالتالي سيتم تعيين قيم العمود row_num بشكل مختلف.
You can see that the row number no longer matches up with IDs.
كما ترى فإن رقم الصف لم يعد يطابق رقم المعرّف ID.
Using the partitioned by clause,
باستخدام بند PARTITION BY،
we can start the count over at 1 again in each partition.
يمكننا إعادة العد من جديد بدءاً بالرقم 1 في كل قسم.
Let's partition by account ID see what this looks like.
لنقسّم حسب معرف الحساب account_id لنرى كيف يبدو ذلك.
There's another function, rank,
هناك دالة أخرى وهي RANK،
that does something similar. Let's take a look.
وهي تؤدي غرضاً مشابهاً. لنلق نظرة.
While this might look the same,
رغم أن هذا قد يبدو مشابهاً لما سبقه،
there is a subtle difference.
إلا أن هناك فرقاً طفيفاً.
If two lines in a row have the same value for occurred at,
إذا كان لسطرين متواليين نفس القيمة في العمود occurred_at،
they're given the same rank,
فإنهما يُمنحان الرتبة نفسها،
whereas row number gives them different numbers.
بينما تعيّن لهما دالة ROW NUMBER رقمين مختلفين.
You'll notice this more if we date trunc the occurred at field by month.
ستلاحظ ذلك أكثر إذا ما استخدمنا DATE_TRUNC على العمود occured_at لاقتطاع الشهر.
As you can see, entries with the same month are now given the same rank,
كما ترى، فإن مدخلات الشهر نفسه قد أسنِدت إليها الرتبة نفسها،
and the rank column then skips some values to make up for it.
ويتخطى عمود الرتبة بعض القيم للتعويض عن ذلك.
There's a similar function,
هناك دالة مشابهة،
dense rank, which doesn't skip values after assigning several rows with the same rank.
وهي DENSE_RANK، وهي لا تتخطى القيم بعد إسناد الرتبة نفسها لعدة صفوف.
So you have this rows skips from rank 2 to rank 4.
أترى كيف ينتقل هذا الصف من الرتبة 2 إلى الرتبة 4. 00:02:20,033 --&gt; 00:00:00,000 لكن مع DENSE_RANK تنتقل من 2 إلى 3 مباشرة.